A Guide to the Norfolk (Va.) Building Inspection Office Architectural Drawings and Plans, 1898-1980
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Norfolk (Va.), Building Inspection Office, Architectural drawings and plans, 1898-1980
Library of Virginia
32256
9,107 sheets, mostly blueprint with some Diazo print and India ink on linen.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
ACCESS TO ARCHITECTURAL AND ENGINEERING PLANS AND DRAWINGS OF CURRENT GOVERNMENTAL BUILDINGS REQUIRES A WRITTEN REQUEST FROM THE PROSPECTIVE USER AND WRITTEN AUTHORIZATION FROM THE APPROPRIATE AUTHORITY WITHIN THE AGENCY OCCUPYING THE FACILITY. SEE LVA ARCHIVES STAFF FOR FURTHER INFORMATION.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Norfolk (Va.) Community Improvement Department, 30 October 1984.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Department of Public Works was created when Norfolk adopted the a City Manager-style system of government in 1917. Section 52 of the city charter sets forth the administrative departments of government- Law, Public Works, Public Welfare, Public Safety, and Finance- under the City Manager. The Director of the Public Works Department was required to be an engineer by profession with experience in municipal engineering. The department would oversee the construction, improvement, repair, maintenance, and use of all public streets, sewers, culverts, canals, viaducts, public highways, sidewalks, drains, ditches, pumping stations, dams, wharves, landings, docks, parks, playgrounds, cemeteries, etc.
Within the Department of Public Works were the City Planning Commission and Board of Dock Commissioners. Walter H. Taylor, Jr. served as the first director of the department.
Scope and Content
This accession consists of the surviving architectural drawings and plans submitted to the City of Norfolk, Building Inspection Office during the building permit application procedure between 1898 and 1980. A building permit was required for alterations and new construction. The structures documented include apartment buildings, banks, churches, commercial buildings, fraternal society buildings, garages, hospitals, hotels, municipal and state government buildings, office buildings, schools, service stations, single and multi-family residences, synagogues, and the like. Of note are drawings for breweries, lard factories, baseball grandstands, bowling alleys, bakeries, fraternal halls, and oyster packaging plants.
Portions of this collection appear to have been discarded by the locality, presumably utilizing some prescribed criteria. However, documentation of those criteria has not been documented. It seems that the drawings were sampled by decade with only drawings from the first year of the decade being retained (Example: 1950, 1960, 1970, etc.). The surviving drawings sometimes include specifications or other documentation, such as correspondence with the building inspectors, and those materials are housed with the drawings. Some of the early decades maintained alteration drawing sets with the original drawings. Where applicable, this has been noted in the finding aid. Additionally, drawing sets for unbuilt projects were also identified and noted. Building type has been noted in the finding aid. The building type was derived from the building's use at the time of processing. For instance, if a skating rink was converted to a warehouse, it is categorized in the finding aid as a warehouse; however, its previous use is also noted. Further, structures with dual uses, such as a warehouse and office building, are categorized by the first use listed in the drawing title. For the purposed of the finding aid, any single or two family residence (duplex) has been considered a residence; dwellings with three or more families have been labeled as apartments. In addition, buildings with associated uses are categorized by that use. For example, a parsonage is listed under "Church/Synagogue" rather than "Residence." Hotels and motels are both listed under the project type "Hotel."
Some early drawings are marked with numbers that appear to be permit numbers; however, because this could not be determined absolutely, no number was recorded in the finding aid. The finding aid includes only numbers recorded after 1970 as "permit number." Due to the inconsistency in permit numbering, each drawing has been assigned a unique control number to facilitate storage and retrieval. The collection is arranged sequentially by control number. The date of the drawing included in the finding aid is the earliest date on all drawing sheets. Revisions or drawing sheets with later dates are not recorded. Additionally, the date may have been derived from associated documents maintained with the drawings. The information recorded as "Tag Number" indicates the year and number assigned to the drawing on a paper disk formerly attached to the drawing roll. The disks were removed but the information was recorded in the finding aid to reflect the localities record keeping system.
Arrangement
Arranged sequentially by LVA control number.
Contents List
- York Street Fire Engine House - Permit Number:, Address: York St., 1898, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 6; Tag Number: 1898-3 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Drawn by: Peebles and Sharpe, Architects, Columbia Building, Norfolk, Va; Commissioned by: City of Norfolk
- Plan Showing Property of Old Dominion S. S. Co., Norfolk, Virginia - Permit Number: None, Address: None, 1898, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 1; Tag Number: 1898-2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Drawn by: John Graham, Jr., C. E.; Notes: Plan shows streets and building footprints.
- Second Presbyterian Church - Permit Number:, Address: None, 1898, Media: Linen, ink; Sheets: 20; Tag Number: (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Drawn by: Carpenter, Breese, and Ferguson, Architects, Norfolk, Va.; Commissioned by: Second Presbyterian Church; Notes: Drawings dated 1898-1901.
- Tilley Memorial M. E. Church - Permit Number: None, Address: Berkley, Va., 1899, Media: Linen, ink; Sheets: 11; Tag Number: 1899-1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Drawn by: J. E. R. Carpenter, Architect, Citzen's Bank Building, Norfolk, Va.; Commissioned by: Tilley Memorial M. E. Church
- Building for Hofheimer Bros. Co. - Permit Number: None, Address: Atlantic St., 1904, Media: Linen, ink; Sheets: 11; Tag Number: (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Drawn by: Neff and Ferguson, Architects, Norfolk, Va.
- The Albemarle for George L. Arps, Esq. - Permit Number: None, Address: 136 Granby St., 1902, Media: Linen, ink; Sheets: 8; Tag Number: 1902-1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Drawn by: Breese and Ferguson, Architects; C. J. Calrow, Supervising Architect; Commissioned by: George L. Arps, Esq.; Notes: Later known as the Town Hotel.
- Store and Office Building for Capt. W. E. Taylor - Permit Number: None, Address: None, 1899, Media: Linen, ink; Sheets: 33; Tag Number: None (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Drawn by: J. E. R. Carpenter, Architect, 502-503 Citizen's Bank Building, Norfolk, Va.; Commissioned by: W. E. Taylor; Notes: Drawing set includes alterations for Messrs. Miller and Rhoads. This building later operated as Miller, Rhoads, and Schwartz.
- Store and Offices for Paul-Gale-Greenwood Co. - Permit Number: None, Address: [222 Granby St.], 1906, Media: Linen, ink, bumwad, blueprints; Sheets: 53; Tag Number: None (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Drawn by: Ferguson and Calrow, Architects, Norfolk, Va.; Notes: Includes alterations to building ca. 1907. Blueprints are heavily damaged.
- Hospital of St. Vincent DePaul - Permit Number: None, Address: Church and Wood Sts., 1899, Media: Linen, ink, bumwad; Sheets: 50; Tag Number: 1899-2 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Drawn by: J. E. R. Carpenter, Architect, 502-503 Citzen's Bank Building, Norfolk, Va.; Notes: Set includes drawings for additional wings ca. 1900.
- The Norfolk Public Library - Permit Number: None, Address: Freemason St., 1903, Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 12; Tag Number: 1903-6 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Drawn by: Herbert D. Hale, Architect; Henry G. Morse, Jr., Associate, 1075 Drexel Building, Philadelphia, Pa.
- Elks Hall for Norfolk Lodge No. 38 - Permit Number: None, Address: 112 College Pl., 1903, Media: Linen, ink, bumwad, blueprint; Sheets: 23; Tag Number: 1903-9 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Drawn by: F. F. Ferguson and Chas. J. Calrow, Architects, Norfolk, Va.; Notes: Includes two sets (one linen, one blueprint). Includes additional blueprint sheet ca. 1933 by Rudolph, Cook, and Van Leewen.
- Chapel Street School - Permit Number: None, Address: Chapel St., 1903, Media: Linen, ink, bumwad, blueprints; Sheets: 22; Tag Number: 1903-5 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Drawn by: John Kevan Peebles, Architect; Notes: Set includes drawings for an addition to the school building, ca. 1906.
- The "Rochambeau" - Permit Number: None, Address: 300-04 Boush St., 1903, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 12; Tag Number: 1903-7 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Drawn by: John Kevan Peebles, Architect; Notes: Later known as the Hotel Preston.
- Business Men's Association Building - Permit Number: None, Address: Plume and Atlantic Sts., 1901, Media: Linen, ink, bumwad; Sheets: 35; Tag Number: None (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Drawn by: John Kevan Peebles, Architect; Notes: Drawings span 1901-1903.
- Building for the Board of Trade and Business Men's Association - Permit Number: None, Address: 300-308 E. Plume St., 1904, Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 15; Tag Number: None (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Drawn by: Neff and Thompson, Architects; Commissioned by: Abbot, Morris, & Co., Agents
- Apartment House for Mr. S. Q. Collins - Permit Number: None, Address: Manteo St., 1908, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 8; Tag Number: 1903-3 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Drawn by: Neff and Thompson, Architects; Commissioned by: S. Q. Collins
- [Glenarm Apartments] - Permit Number: None, Address: 3613 Granby St., n.d., Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 2; Tag Number: None (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Notes: Information taken from sticker on outside of roll.
- Offices, Stables, and Storage Plant for The L. Hoster Brewing Co. at Norfolk, Va. - Permit Number: None, Address: Kelley St., 1903, Media: Kraft paper, blueprints; Sheets: 10; Tag Number: 1903-8 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Drawn by: Vance Hebard, Architect, 76 Charlotte St., Norfolk, Va.; Commissioned by: L. Hoster Brewing Co.; Notes: 1903 DRAWINGS ARE VERY FRAGILE. Second set of blueprints dates from 3/6/1906 and are for a cold storage addition.
- The Merrimac Apartments - Permit Number: None, Address: 338 Boush St., 1904, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 4; Tag Number: 1904-2 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Drawn by: F. F. Ferguson and Chas. J. Calrow, Architects, Norfolk, Va.; Commissioned by: The Merrimac Corp.; Notes: Contains only floor plans and plumbing details. Obvious during processing that additional sheets were ripped from the bound set.
- Imperial Apartments - Permit Number: None, Address: 411 Freemason St., 1903, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 6; Tag Number: 1903-2 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Drawn by: Co-Op Building Plan Association, Architects, 203 Broadway, N.Y.C.; Commissioned by: R. Margoles
- The Sommerville Apartment House - Permit Number: None, Address: 502-506 Mowbray Ave., 1903, Media: Linen, ink; Sheets: 13; Tag Number: None (Box 2, Folder 21)
  Drawn by: F. F. Ferguson and Chas. J. Calrow, Architects, Norfolk, Va.; Commissioned by: T. S. Southgate, Esq.; Notes: Tag on drawings [removed] noted that structure was "never built."
- Elizabeth Apartments - Permit Number: None, Address: None, 1903, Media: Linen, ink; Sheets: 4; Tag Number: None (Box 2, Folder 22)
  Drawn by: Neff and Thompson, Architects, Norfolk, VA; Commissioned by: Old Dominion Mortgage and Trust Co.
- Building for the Merchants and Mechanics Bank, Norfolk, Va. - Permit Number: None, Address: 127 Bank St., 1903, Media: Linen, ink, blueprints; Sheets: 18; Tag Number: 1903-1 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  Drawn by: John Kevan Peebles, Architect, Norfolk, Va.; Notes: Includes a set of detail drawings for channel and beam layout. Set includes drawings for rear addition to bank building ca. 1904.
- Alterations at #222 Granby St., Norfolk, VA, for Paul-Gale-Greenwood Co. - Permit Number: None, Address: 222 Granby St., 1919, Media: Linen, ink; Sheets: 4; Tag Number: None (Box 3, Folder 24)
  Drawn by: Peebles and Ferguson, Architects, Norfolk, Va.; Commissioned by: Paul-Gale-Greenwood Co.
- Building for the Jacob Hecht Estate, Corner Tazewell and Duke Sts., Norfolk, Va. - Permit Number: None, Address: Tazewell and Duke Sts., 1906, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 15; Tag Number: 1903-4 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  Drawn by: Breese and Mitchell, Architects, Atlantic Trust Building, Norfolk, Va.; Commissioned by: Jacob Hecht Estate; Notes: Includes one drawing sheet for later alteration/maintenance, ca. 1939-40.
- Ghent Chapel, Norfolk, Va. - Permit Number: None, Address: Stockley Gardens and Olney Rd., 1904, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 2; Tag Number: None (Box 3, Folder 26)
  Drawn by: John Kevan Peebles, Architect; Commissioned by: Ghent Episcopal Congregation; Notes: Drawings are heavily damaged and torn. Mended as possible.
- Store for Messrs. Ames, Brownley, and Hornthall - Permit Number: None, Address: 400 Granby St., 1902, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 34; Tag Number: 1902-2 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  Drawn by: Breese and Ferguson, Architects; Commissioned by: Ames, Brownly, and Hornthall; Notes: 1902 drawings are heavily damaged. Includes additions and alterations through 1911by F. F. Ferguson and C. J. Caldrow (3/21/1907) and Ferguson, Caldrow and Taylor (5/8/1911).
- Building for Geo. W. Day and Sons - Permit Number: None, Address: Plume St., 1904, Media: Linen, ink; Sheets: 7; Tag Number: 1904-6 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  Drawn by: Neff and Thompson, Architects, Norfolk, VA; Commissioned by: Geo. W. Dey and Sons
- Alterations for Mr. R. Randolph Hicks - Permit Number: 7534, Address: 301 Charlotte St., 1904, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 7; Tag Number: 1904-13 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  Drawn by: Mitchell and Wilcox, Architects, 604-608 Paul-Gale-Greenwood Building, Norfolk, Va.; Commissioned by: R. Randolph Hicks
- Alterations at the Haddington Building, Norfolk, Virginia, for Mr. Meredith S. Spratley - Permit Number: None, Address: Granby St. and City Hall Ave., 1904, Media: Linen, ink, bumwad, blueprints; Sheets: 29; Tag Number: 1904-7 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  Drawn by: F. F. Ferguson and Chas. J. Calrow, Architects, Norfolk, Va.; Commissioned by: Meredith S. Spratley; Notes: Includes drawings and specifications for alterations ca. 1923 by Philip B. Moser and Erwin C. Gutzwiller, Architects and Engineers, Norfolk, Va.
- Three Stores on Brewer Street for Mr. Henry Kirn - Permit Number: None, Address: Brewer St., 1904, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 5; Tag Number: 1904-4 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  Drawn by: C. R. Parlett, Builder, 14 Lowenberg Building, Norfolk, Va.; Contractor: C.R. Parlett; Commissioned by: Henry Kirn; Notes: Year taken from discarded acidic paper wrapper.
- Building for the Ghent Club, Norfolk, Va. - Permit Number: None, Address: Olney Rd., 1904, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 9; Tag Number: 1904-10 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  Drawn by: Neff and Thompson, Architects, 390 Withers Building,Norfolk, VA; Commissioned by: D. Lowenberg
- Grace Baptist Church [and Parsonage] - Permit Number: None, Address: Wood and Chapel Sts., 1904, Media: Linen, ink, bumwad; Sheets: 21; Tag Number: 1904-11 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  Drawn by: F. F. Ferguson and Chas. J. Calrow, Architects, Norfolk, Va.; Commissioned by: Grace Baptist Church; Notes: Parsonage drawings date 6/14/1904. Drawing set includes sketches for church building.
- Skating Rink, Norfolk, Va., for the Iceum Co. - Permit Number: None, Address: Main St., 1904, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 17; Tag Number: None (Box 4, Folder 34)
  Drawn by: Arnold Eberhard, Architect, 505-507 Citizens Bank Building, Norfolk, Va.; Commissioned by: The Iceum Co.; Notes: Includes two sets of drawings dated December 1904. Building later used for storage.
- Offices for Messrs. Byrd and Baldwin Bros. - Permit Number: None, Address: 116 Brook Ave., 1904, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 9; Tag Number: None (Box 4, Folder 35)
  Drawn by: F. F. Ferguson and Chas. J. Calrow, Architects, Norfolk, Va.; Commissioned by: Baldwin Bros.
- Agency at Norfolk, Va., for Portner Brewing Co., Alexandria, Va. - Permit Number: None, Address: 17-19 Madison St., 1904, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 6; Tag Number: None (Box 4, Folder 36)
  Drawn by: Oscar G. Vogt, Architect, Room 68, Corcoran Building, Washington, DC; Commissioned by: Robert Portner Brewing Co.; Notes: Building later used as a warehouse.
- The Holland Apartments - Permit Number: None, Address: De Bree Pl. [Drummon Pl.) and Botetourt St., 1904, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 8; Tag Number: 1904-1, 1904-12 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  Drawn by: Neff and Thompson, Architects; Commissioned by: The Holland Reality Corporation
- The Vendome - Permit Number: None, Address: Colonial Ave., 1904, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 16; Tag Number: None (Box 4, Folder 38)
  Drawn by: John Kevan Peebles, Architect, Norfolk, Va.; Notes: Building later known as The Regent Apartments. Set includes alterations 5/17/1926, Meredith and Tazewell, Contractors, Permit # 21779.
- Building for Atlantic Trust and Deposit Co. - Permit Number: None, Address: 111 W. Main St., 1904, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 22; Tag Number: 1904-15 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  Drawn by: Neff and Thompson, Architects; Commissioned by: Atlantic Trust and Deposit Co.; Notes: Includes correspondence with the Norfolk Building Inspection Office ca. 1924. Building later known as Virginia National Bank.
- Brambleton Public School Number 1 - Permit Number: None, Address: None, 1910, Media: Linen, ink, bumwad; Sheets: 11; Tag Number: 1910-7 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  Drawn by: Ferguson, Calrow, and Taylor, Architects
- Atlantic City Public School Number 2 - Permit Number: None, Address: Graydon Ave., 1910, Media: Linen, ink, blueprints; Sheets: 23; Tag Number: 1910-5, 1910-10 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  Drawn by: Ferguson, Calrow, and Taylor, Architects; Notes: Includes two sets for original constructions (linen, blueprint), one set (6 sheets) for an addition by Benjamin F. Mitchell, Architect, 8/19/1912, and an undated drawing for alterations and additions by Calrow, Browne, and Fitz-gibbon. Later known as the Robert E. Lee School.
- [Store] - Permit Number: None, Address: 805 Liberty St., 1910, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 7; Tag Number: 1910-4 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: Abe Legum; Notes: Information taken from acidic wrapper.
- New High School Building for the City of Norfolk, Va. - Permit Number: None, Address: 15th St. b/t De Bree and Moran Sts., 1910, Media: Linen, ink, blueprints; Sheets: 34; Tag Number: 1910-1 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  Drawn by: Neff and Thompson, Architects; Notes: Includes plans for alterations and additions to school building dated 6/26/1915 and 8/27/1920 by Neff and Thompson.
- Store Building for W. A. Jones, Esq. - Permit Number: None, Address: 601-607 Botetourt St., 1910, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 3; Tag Number: 1910-6 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  Drawn by: Neff and Thompson, Architects; Commissioned by: W. A. Jones
- Plans for Upton Realty Corporation - Permit Number: None, Address: 1111 E. Main St., 1910, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 7; Tag Number: 1910-8 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: L. J. Upton
- Apartment Building for J. W. Cole, Esq. - Permit Number: None, Address: 721 Raleigh Ave., 1910, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 8; Tag Number: 1910-3 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  Drawn by: Benjamin F. Mitchell, Architect,; Commissioned by: J. W. Cole; Notes: Known as the Traymore Apts.
- Police and Fire Station, Berkley Ward - Permit Number: None, Address: Liberty St., 1910, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 7; Tag Number: 1910-2 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  Drawn by: Lee and Diehl, Architects, Norfolk, Virginia
- Club House for the Norfolk Lodge No. 38 B. P. O. E. - Permit Number: None, Address: None, 1912, Media: Linen, ink; Sheets: 11; Tag Number: None (Box 5, Folder 48)
  Drawn by: Ferguson, Calrow, and Taylor, Architects, Norfolk, Va.
- Addition to Nurses Home, Norfolk Protestant Hospital - Permit Number: None, Address: 841 Raleigh, n.d., Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 4; Tag Number: None (Box 5, Folder 49)
  Drawn by: Calrow, Browne, and Fitz-gibbon, Architects
- Apartment Building for Anna L. Morris Meghan - Permit Number: None, Address: Holt St. and Arlington Pl., 1910, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 7; Tag Number: 1910-13 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: Anna L. Morris Meghan; Notes: Later known as Panacea Apartments.
- Building for Fergus Reid, Esq., Granby St., Norfolk, Va. - Permit Number: None, Address: 406-408 Granby St., 1910, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 30; Tag Number: 1910-12 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  Drawn by: Benjamin F. Mitchell, Architect, Norfolk, Va.; Commissioned by: Fergus Reid; Notes: Contains three sets of drawings the original cited above (12 sheets), a set for alterations by B. F. Mitchell on 10/7/1918 (7 sheets), and another set for alterations by Bernard B. Spigel, ca. 1938-1939 (11 sheets).
- Norfolk Protestant Hospital - Permit Number: None, Address: None, 1906, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 15; Tag Number: None (Box 6, Folder 52)
  Drawn by: Taylor and Hepburn, Architects, Norfolk, Va.
- Ghent Presbyterian Church - Permit Number: None, Address: None, 1910, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 16; Tag Number: 1910-11 (Box 12, Folder 53)
  Drawn by: Ferguson, Calrow, and Taylor, Architects; Notes: Heavily damaged and torn.
- Brown Savings and Banking Company, Incorporated - Permit Number: None, Address: N E Corner, Church and Queen Sts., 1920, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 23; Tag Number: 1920-37 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  Drawn by: Benjamin F. Mitchell, Architect, Norfolk, Va.; Commissioned by: Brown Savings and Banking Company, Inc.; Notes: Includes additional drawings sets and specifications for alterations to the structure dated 3/21/1932 (4 sheets) and 5/1941(2 sheets), all by Benjamin F. Mitchell, Architect. Later known as Metropolitan Bank.
- Plan for an Additional Story of Warehouse for M. and I. L. Brenner on Cove and Walke Sts. - Permit Number: None, Address: Cove and Walke Sts., 1920, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 8; Tag Number: 1920-38 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  Drawn by: Unsigned; Commissioned by: M. and I. L. Brenner
- Refinery for Wynne Lard and Provision Company - Permit Number: None, Address: 1148 May Ave., 1920, Media: Linen, ink, Blueprints; Sheets: 44; Tag Number: None (Box 6, Folder 56)
  Drawn by: Peebles and Ferguson, Architects, Norfolk, Va.; Commissioned by: Wynne Lard and Provision Co.; Notes: Includes two additional sets dated 3/6/1933 by Armour and Co., Engineering Div., (2 sheets) and ca. 12/12/1930 by Rudolph, Cook, and Van Leeuwen (9 sheets) for alterations to the factory building. Later known as Hemphill Packing Co.
- Lydia H. Roper Home - Permit Number: None, Address: 40th St. and Columbus Ave., 1920, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 14; Tag Number: 1920-33 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  Drawn by: Peebles and Ferguson, Architects, Norfolk, Va.
- Store Buildings on Granby St. - Permit Number: None, Address: 436-442 Granby St., 1910, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 6; Tag Number: 1920-36 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  Drawn by: Rossel Edward Mitchell, Architect, Dickson Bldg.; Commissioned by: Mr. T. S. Southgate (No. 2, 3, 4); Mrs. J. P. Johnson (No. 1)
- Home for the Keyser-Doherty Printing Corp. - Permit Number: None, Address: Hall St., n.d., Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 5; Tag Number: None (Box 6, Folder 59)
  Drawn by: Bernard B. Spigel, Architect; Commissioned by: Keyser-Doherty Printing Corp.
- Store for Mr. J. H. Cofer - Permit Number: None, Address: 433 Granby St., 1920, Media: Linen, ink; Sheets: 1; Tag Number: 1920-41 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  Drawn by: Neff and Thompson, Architects and Engineers; Commissioned by: J. H. Cofer
- Store Building for Mr. S. D. Scott - Permit Number: None, Address: 208-310 Brewer St., 1920, Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 2; Tag Number: 1920-31 (Box 6, Folder 61)